It shows up now of all times?
Give me a break.
Due to the current emergency situation,
all phone lines have been suspended.
No good, huh?
My cellphone has no bars.
The buses and trains have all stopped too.
I guess she won't be coming...
It can't be helped.
I should head to a shelter.
Focus all fire on the target!
Sorry for the wait!
The target is still intact.
It is progressing toward Tokyo-3.
The Air Force is unable to damage it!
Throw everything at it! Mobilize the Fourth Armored Division to intercept!
Don't hold back!
Destroy the target at all cost!
How the hell?!
That was a direct hit!
The tank battalion was completely destroyed.
Missiles had no effect on it...
It's no use! We need more firepower!
As we thought, there's an AT Field...
Yes.
Conventional weapons are useless against the Angel.
Understood.
We will proceed as planned.
No way...
They're using an N² Mine?!
Get down!
We did it!
I'm afraid we've left nothing for you to do.
Shockwave incoming!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I just have some dirt in my mouth.
That's to be expected.
Now...
Are you ready?
And... push!
Thanks a lot.
Good job.
No, I should be thanking you, Katsuragi-san.
You can call me Misato.
It's nice to meet you, Ikari Shinji-kun.
You too.
What is the target's status?
Monitoring is not possible due to radio noise.
Restoring image.
Our final plan failed...
How is this possible...
It's a monster!
Thank goodness Luno still moves.
It wouldn't be funny if my car was destroyed before I paid off my twelve month loan.
I have a direct express train there,
so hopefully we'll get there in time.
So... don't you have any questions, Shinji-kun?
No.
I've been the only one talking.
Oh, sorry.
You don't have to apologize.
Just... aren't you curious what that giant thing was?
Or maybe just what's happening?
Don't you want to know?
Well, um...
I just thought I wouldn't get an answer either way.
You get too considerate and decide things on your own.
You should act more like a kid.
I don't care.
I'm just doing as my teacher told.
I see.
Well, all right.
By the way, that thing back there was an unidentified life form known as an Angel.
The fourth Angel.
Its self-regenerating ability is quite impressive.
It's a self-completing semi-perfect organism.
It's no surprise.
An existence that ate the fruit of life.
Indeed.
An existence that exists to annihilate those who ate the fruit of knowledge: us.
The gate will be closing.
Please be careful.
Secret military agency, Nerve?
Yeah, it's a private organization under the direct supervision of the United Nations.
It's where my father is, right?
Well, yeah...
Do you know what he does?
"Work of utmost importance for the protection of humanity."
That's what my teacher said.
From this point on, you will be in command of this operation.
Show us your capabilities.
Understood.
Ikari-kun, from our available weapons, we admit that we have no effective means of disabling the target.
Are you confident you can succeed?
It is why Nerve exists.
Are we heading to where my father is?
Well, yes.
We are.
Father...
Oh, were you given an I.D. by your father?
Yeah.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Here, read this.
Nerve...
My father's work.
Is there something I'm needed for?
Of course.
He wouldn't send me a letter unless he needed me somehow.
I see.
You don't get along with your father.
Same here.
Amazing!
It's a real GeoFront!
Yeah.
This is our secret base: Nerve Headquarters.
It's the foundation for rebuilding our world and the last defense for humanity.
Let's see...
Leave the West Entrance at the station...
go right at North Gate-03...
go into Route-08...
This facility is structured like a maze for some reason.
I think this is the correct route...
Um, are we lost?
I'm not used to this yet.
Well, I'm sure we'll get there as long as we're moving!
Second phase cooling complete.
All personnel return.
Finish defrosting the left arm's transmission in three minutes,
and do not forget to extract the apoptosis data.
Roger.
Reporting to Dr. Akagi:
Lieutenant Colonel Katsuragi of the Strategic Department, and one other, have arrived in S-36.
Incredible.
You're late again.
A-Ah... Ritsuko!
You're twelve minutes over the estimated arrival time.
I came to welcome you since you're so late, Lieutenant Colonel Katsuragi.
We don't have the time or the manpower.
Eh... Sorry.
This is the man's son?
Yep.
I'm the Director of the First Science Division of Project E, Akagi Ritsuko.
It's nice to meet you.
You too.
Well then, I'll leave the rest to you.
Meeting his son after 3 years...
Sub Commander.
The target is beginning to move.
All right.
All hands to level one battle stations.
I repeat:
Prepare for anti-land ambush.
Ikari Shinij-kun, there's something I want to show you.
This is the ultimate humanoid fighting machine.
The artificial human, Evangelion.
That is Unit-01.
It is our last and greatest weapon.
This is my father's work?
Correct.
It's been a while.
Father...
Prepare to sortie.
Sortie?!
But Unit-00 is still frozen!
Unless... you intend to use Unit-01?
There is no other choice.
Ikari Shinji-kun...
Yes?
You will pilot it.
Why did you call me here, Father?
You know why.
So, you want me to pilot this and fight that thing outside?
Correct.
No, I won't!
Not after all this time!
For so long I've thought you didn't care about me!
I called you because I need you.
Father, why me?
Because it's impossible for any other human.
I can't do it...
I've never seen or heard of this thing.
It's impossible!
You will be instructed.
No...
I can't do it!
I can't pilot this!
If you're going to pilot it, do it now.
Otherwise...
leave!
We've been found...
Damage to layers 01 and 08.
Shinji-kun, there isn't much time.
Conflagrations in Block-D. Closing all passages to the area.
Pilot it!
No...
After coming all this way, this is ridiculous!
Shinji-kun, why did you come here?
Don't run away from your father, and above all, from yourself!
I know!
But, I can't do it!
Fuyutsuki.
Wake up Rei.
Can we use her?
She's not dead.
Understood.
Rei.
Yes.
The spare is useless.
You will do it again.
Yes.
Restart Unit-01's core unit to L-00 Type.
Roger.
Discontinuing current process. Beginning reformat.
Restarting the startup command.
I'm useless again...
as expected...
The target has crossed the absolute line of defense.
It is proceeding further in.
Are you okay?!
I mustn’t run away, I mustn’t run away, I mustn’t run away, I mustn’t run away...
I'll do it.
I'll pilot it.
Freezing process has been halted.
Flywheel rotation has stopped.
Connections have been released.
No problems with auxiliary voltage.
Stoplight plug draining is complete.
Roger, inserting Entry Plug.
Spinal conduction system opened, connection established.
Probe needle driving in.
Prime synch established.
Analyzing nerve connections.
Reading of -0.051% within limitations.
The plug has been fixed.
Roger.
Starting first contact.
Flooding Entry Plug.
What is this?!
It's all right.
Once the LCL fills your lungs, it will provide oxygen directly to your blood.
You'll get used to it.
Master power source connection complete.
Roger.
Starting second contact.
Establishing interface.
No problems detected in A10 nervous system.
LCL levels nominal.
Japanese has been fixed as the primary mode of operation.
No problems detected with initial contacts.
Communication lines open.
Up to list 1405, all clear.
Synapse reading: Synchro rate 41.3%.
And he's not even wearing a Plug Suit!
Amazing.
Harmonics are at normal levels.
Everything's under control.
This will work!
Prepare to launch!
Release primary lock bolts!
Primary locks released.
Releasing umbilical bridge.
Release secondary lock bolts!
Removing primary restraints.
Removing secondary restraints.
Releasing safety devices one through fifteen.
Safety devices released.
Unit-01 is now free.
Internal power supply charge complete.
No problems detected with external power supply.
Understood.
Evangelion Unit-01 transferring to launch pad.
No problems with the linear rail track.
Electromagnetic guidance is in regular operation.
Unit-01 is currently moving through K-52.
Proceeding in accordance to the launch sequence.
Eva has reached the ejection sub terminal.
Launch destination configured at ground level 0.
The course is clear. All green!
Launch preparations complete.
Understood.
Are you sure?
Of course.
We must defeat the Angels, or we will all die here.
Ikari, are you really okay with this?
Launch!
Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Release the final safety lock!
Evangelion Unit-01, lift off!
Shinji-kun,
focus only on walking now.
Walk...
It walked!
Shinji-kun, get up!
Hurry!
Get up right now!
Shinji-kun, calm down!
That isn't your arm!
How is the Evangelion's defense system?
I can't get a signal.
The field isn't developing.
No good?
The left arm has been fractured!
The circuits have snapped!
Shinji-kun, dodge it!
The frontal cranium has been cracked!
The armor can't withstand much more!
Skull fractured! Damage unknown!
A problem has occurred in the operating system!
Status report!
Synchro graph inverting.
Pulse-flow is reversing!
Cut the circuits!
Stop it at once!
It's no good!
The signal is being rejected! It's not connecting!
What about Shinji-kun?!
No response from the monitoring system.
Life signs unknown!
Unit-01 is completely silent.
Misato!
It's come to this...
Halt military operations!
The pilot's life is our main priority!
Eject the plug by force!
It's no good!
It's not responding!
What is this?!
Eva has reactivated!
Impossible...
It shouldn't be able to move!
Has it gone...
...berserk?!
We've won.
AT Field!
Unless the AT Field is breached...
...you won't be able to do anything to it.
Left arm restored.
Amazing!
Unit-01 has also raised an AT Field!
Angel phase space being neutralized.
No, it's corroding it.
It broke through that AT Field like it was nothing...
Is Eva...
This must be Eva's...
...true form.
Have you decided on a name?
If it's a boy, Shinji.
If it's a girl, then Rei.
Shinji...
Rei...
Ayanami...
Shinji...
Rei...
Ikari...
That's not right...
Ayanami...
Rei!
I don't know this ceiling.
The attack of the fourth Angel, and its defeat...
Then the discovery of the Third Child
and the activation of Eva Unit-01.
All of this was predetermined.
Repairing Unit-01 is a large unexpected cost.
That is hardly a problem compared to a frozen Unit-00.
Eva Unit-01's recovery operation is complete.
It is currently locked in Cage Six.
A ten day examination is scheduled.
And the recording from when it went berserk?
It was functioning at zero capacity. Nothing was recorded.
Reason unknown, huh?
Trusting it as an effective weapon
might be a little difficult.
Inconveniences aside, Unit-01 needs to perform at least until the fifth Angel.
Don't worry.
Unit-01 is not our only weapon.
Unit-02's pilot is currently being evaluated in Germany.
The construction of Unit-03 is also progressing as planned.
Your primary duty is to oversee Nerve and Eva with discretion.
We will not stand for any repeated disappointments.
That's right.
To exterminate the Angels is but one step in fulfilling our contract with Lilith.
The Human Instrumentality Project...
Human Instrumentality Project
27th Interim Report
Top Secret
This should be your top priority, understood?
I understand.
Everything will go according to Seele's scenario.
The complete collapse of the Angel's AT Field was far beyond our expectations.
The blood is like a lake from hell...
It reminds me of the Second Impact.
It makes me sick.
Eva can defeat the Angels.
That fact alone is enough of a hope for humanity.
It's the pilot who carries the burden of that hope.
Alone?
That's right.
His room's in Block Six. I assume that isn't a problem.
That's fine.
Is that really okay,
Shinji-kun?
It's okay, I prefer being alone.
It's always the same wherever I am.
What?!
Like I was saying, Shinji-kun would be much better off at my place.
Besides, I have authorization.
Don't worry, it's not like I'll have my hands all over him.
That goes without saying!
Have you no shame?!
She really can't take a joke...
All right, looks like we're having a party tonight!
What for?
To welcome my new roommate of course!
So you're going to move after all?
Yes.
I never thought this city would become a battlefield.
Really! My husband said we should evacuate soon.
Just today, over one hundred people left the city.
Is that right?
No matter how powerful a fortress this city is, those Nerve people still don't know what they're doing.
Just thinking about yesterday makes me shudder...
I know...
Sorry,
but we'll be making a quick stop on the way.
Where to?
A really cool place.
The city...
It seems so lonely.
It's time.
Amazing...
The buildings are growing!
This is our stronghold against the onslaught of Angels,
Tokyo-3.
This is our home...
and the city you protected.
I think your things have already been delivered.
To be honest, I've only moved here recently.
All right, come on in.
U-Um...
Pardon the intrusion.
Shinji-kun, this is your home now.
I-I'm home.
Welcome home.
Ah yeah...
It's a little messy in here. Don't mind it though.
A little...
messy?
Oh sorry, could you put the food in the fridge please?
Y-Yes!
Ice...
Junk food...
And nothing but beer?
What kind of life does she lead?
Let's eat!
Let's eat.
I love it! I live for this!
Not hungry?
It's pretty good for instant food.
Ah, well... I'm just not used to this sort of meal.
No way!
You can't be so picky!
No, that's not it...
U-Um...
Pretty fun, huh?
Having a meal with another person?
Yes.
All right!
Since this is your home now,
you have to act like it!
Y-Yes.
Come on...
"Yes, yes, yes, yes." Don't be so boring!
You're a boy, aren't you?!
Pull yourself together!
Yes.
Well, whatever.
Go take a bath and wash away all that negativity.
Bathing is the laundry of life!
M-M-Misato-san!
What?
Oh, him?
He's my hot-weather penguin friend.
A bird like that exists?!
They did 15 years ago.
There were so many of them.
His name is Pen-Pen.
He'll be your other roommate in this house.
Anyway... shouldn't you be hiding that?
A little obvious, don't you think?
Maybe I'm the one who'll be seen through...
Katsuragi Misato-san...
She's not a bad person.
Bathing is the laundry of life!
More bad memories come up in here than others.
What is Rei's current state?
Did you go to the hospital at noon?
There are no problems.
Preparations to restart the frozen Unit-00 come first.
Is your son's current condition acceptable?
His mental state must be very unstable.
He's been released.
Still, his condition is a good excuse to cancel the freezing of Unit-00.
Yes... It was Lieutenant Colonel Katsuragi's proposal after all.
Even without a preliminary report, they suddenly elected him the Third Child.
And as if in response, the fourth Angel attacked.
In addition, Commander Ikari forces his son to pilot.
There must be some resentment.
But still,
knowing the Angel has been defeated, I feel surprisingly...
unhappy.
Another ceiling I don't know...
That's no surprise.
Because I don't know anything of this city.
This is your home now.
Why am I here?
Shinji-kun? I'm coming in.
I forgot to tell you something.
You did a good thing.
You should be proud.
Goodnight, Shinji-kun.
Hang in there.
Sorry, exchange student.
I have to hit you.
I just won't be satisfied if I don't.
Real sorry.
That guy's little sister was injured in that big incident the other day.
Well, something like that.
It's not like I piloted it because I wanted to.
What part of this is being praised?
If it was such a good thing to pilot Eva, why am I getting hit?
Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Within an Angel is a central core.
Destroying it is the only way to kill an Angel.
Therefore, always aim for the center, and pull the switch.
We will work on accuracy.
You will remember the sensation when the time comes.
Yes.
Good.
We will continue practice in Induction Mode.
Yes.
Shinji-kun sure has brought himself around to piloting Eva, hasn't he?
He does whatever people tell him to.
It's how he gets through life.
Position the target in the center... pull the switch.
That reminds me...
Shinji-kun was hit by a student at his new school.
Is his security detail working all right?
There's no problem with the secret agency's surveillance.
Besides, it wasn't very bad.
It was better for there to be no outside interference.
Doesn't he live with you?
His care is your responsibility too, you know.
It's for that reason.
It's difficult... He's just too naive.
Is that a complaint?
You were the one who was so adamant about taking him in.
Shut up...
That's right.
Well, he doesn't have much of a personality for making friends.
Have you heard of the "Hedgehog's dilemma"?
Hedgehog?
The little prickly things?
If a hedgehog wants to be close with other hedgehogs...
the closer they become, the more they hurt each other.
People are the same way.
The same is true of Shinji-kun.
Within his heart he remembers the pain of being hurt,
so he cowers away.
Year 2 Class A
Well, eventually he'll realize.
Growing up means
being hurt whether you're close with others,
or if they're kept at a distance.
I suppose you're right.
Still, when will we get the B-Section equipment repair estimate?
Eva's maintenance and battle capacity is their main priority.
They probably don't have money for this.
My butt is freezing...
An emergency call...
I'll go on ahead.
The object has been visually identified.
E747 has also confirmed the object.
Analysis indicates Pattern Blue.
There's no doubt that it's the fifth Angel.
All hands to level one battle stations.
Roger.
Preparing anti-aircraft measures.
Tokyo-3 transforming to battle formation.
Initiating Central Block.
Districts One through Seven of Central Block transferred.
Notification to all government ministries completed.
Target is steadily progressing.
All anti-aircraft systems currently functioning at 48%.
What is the status of civilians and noncombatants?
Reports confirm that they have already been evacuated to shelters.
All Elementary and Middle School student classes,
please gather in your designated blocks.
There is a lost child at shelter number 323 in Sector Seven.
At it again?
There's only letters on the screen again.
It's an information blackout.
They won't show us regular citizens anything,
even if this is a big event.
They're just wasting tax money...
Some people in this world need those bullets to be used.
The Japanese government is demanding we send out an Evangelion.
How annoying.
It's not like we weren't going to anyway.
Starting Entry Plug.
LCL levels nominal...
Crimp lock released.
Father isn't even here.
Why am I piloting this again?
Even though I got beat up...
Hey, I wanna talk to you about something.
What about?
Come here.
Fine...
Yeah, yeah! That's what I thought.
Class Rep!
What?
We both have to go to the john apparently.
Come on, you had your chance earlier!
So, what's this about?
Before I die, I'm going to see at least one of them.
That battle up there?
It's the real thing!
Who knows when the next enemy will come here.
Kensuke, you're nuts.
If I miss this chance, I might never get another!
Come on... Just help me open the gate.
Guess I've got no choice.
You sure don't give in, do you?
Shinji-kun, are you ready to sortie?
Yes.
Good.
Neutralize the enemy's AT Field, then rapidly fire with the gatling gun.
Just like in practice. You'll be fine.
Yes.
Launch!
Incredible!
This was worth the trouble!
Just in time!
It's here.
Position the target in the center... pull the switch...
AT Field is developing.
Position target in the center... pull the switch...
Just as planned.
Are you ready, Shinji-kun?
Yes.
Idiot!
The smoke is concealing the enemy!
Looks like it got him.
He'll be all right.
We're sending up a reserve rifle!
Take it!
Shinji-kun...?
Shinji-kun?!
Oh man...
He must still be messed up from when you hit him.
Sh-Shut up!
Umbilical Cable has been disconnected!
Eva switching to internal power!
Active time remaining is 4 minutes 53 seconds!
It's coming this way!
Shinji-kun, are you all right?
Shinji-kun!
Can he hear me?
No problems detected.
It should run!
Shinji-kun's classmates?!
What are they doing there?!
Why won't he fight it?!
He can't move because we're here!
Unit-01 will reach active time limit in 3 minutes 28 seconds!
Contact with outer surface, damage at 58%!
Shinji-kun, let those two into the cockpit!
Retreat once they're in.
We'll regroup later.
You two, get in quickly!
What? There's water!
LCL levels nominal.
My camera!
Entry Plug restarting.
Penetrating through third protection film!
Now! Retreat!
Take recovery Route 34.
Head to the mountain's eastern side!
Exchange student, she said "retreat!"
I mustn’t run away...
Exchange student!
Progressive Knife equipped!
Shinji-kun, listen to me!
Fall back now!
Shinji-kun!
That idiot!
Unit-01 will reach active time limit in 30 seconds.
28, 27, 26...
25, 24, 23, 22...
13, 12, 11, 10, 9...
8, 7, 6, 5...
4, 3, 2, 1...
Eva Unit-01 has ceased all activity.
The target has completely collapsed.
Why did you ignore my orders?
I'm sorry.
I'm the one responsible for this military operation, correct?
Yes.
When I give you an order, it is your duty to follow them.
Do you understand me?
Yes.
Make this the last time.
Do you really understand what I'm telling you?!
Yes.
I understand, Misato-san.
It's fine since we won, right?
If you tell me to pilot Eva, I will.
That's enough.
Go back and get some rest.
The next station is Naga'o Toge.
Please exit to the right.
He has no intention of coming back.
That idiot.
Ikari, Ikari Shinji.
Year 2 Class A
What's this?
Absent so soon after transferring...
Well regardless, I'll hand back yesterday's test.
Okay, fine...
Take me back to Misato-san's place!
Did walking around for days cheer you up, Ikari Shinji-kun?
Not really.
It doesn't matter what I do.
I'm not free to do anything.
I have to pilot the Eva regardless.
It's the only reason my father called me here.
Fine.
I'll pilot it.
If that's what everyone wants, that's what I'll do.
What everyone wants?
What do you want?
I know I can't do it...
Everyone knows it.
Father, Misato-san, even an injured Ayanami-
Cut it out!
This has nothing to do with anyone else!
You decide whether you continue to pilot Eva.
If you want to leave this terrible place, fine!
It's all up to you.
Do as you please!
In the end, your son acted as planned.
Yes.
Next we will have Rei move in closer to him.
The plan has not changed.
A 14 year old scenario...
Our fate rests on children.
Isn't it a bit cruel?
No holding back.
Go ahead and hit me!
I won't feel satisfied if you don't.
Well, seeing as he's so sincere, I'd go for it.
Now we're even.
Im sorry for hitting you, Ikari.
Go for it, Tayoko!
If you lose, you're paying for pizza!
All right, keep it up!
Go!
Please, make me go one more-
Hey, they're looking over here!
Pervs!
No way!
Suzuhara has a weird look in his eyes.
Ikari-kun!
Ayanami Rei, age 14.
She was the first candidate chosen by the Marduk Report.
The First Child.
Specifically, she is the exclusive pilot of the experimental Evangelion Unit-00.
Her personal history is non-existent.
Everything has been erased.
Why did my father rescue her?
Start-up system corrupt!
Problem detected in Stage 3.
Nervous system elements rejected.
Pulse-flow is reversing!
Unable to stop it!
Direct monitoring disrupted.
Entry Plug in unstable depths.
Eva is refusing to release it!
Halt all contacts.
Break circuits 1 through 6.
It's no good, the signal isn't connecting!
Eva Unit-00 is out of control!
Stop the experiment.
Cut all power.
Yes, sir!
Unit-00 is currently on reserve power.
Complete shutdown in 35 seconds!
Suspension in process.
It's dangerous! Step back!
Auto-ejection system engaging!
Oh, no!
Quickly, release the bakelite!
Rei!
Complete shutdown in 10 seconds!
8, 7, 6, 5...
4, 3, 2, 1.
Unit-00 has ceased all activity.
Rei, are you okay?!
Rei!
Good.
It's rather unbelievable, isn't it?
Despite the official report having been destroyed, it's all true.
To unfreeze Unit-00 after it just went berserk...
Isn't that a bit hasty?
Another Angel suddenly appeared.
Our combat readiness is an urgent priority.
I suppose that's true...
Rei's restart test has already been authorized.
Using Unit-00 won't be a problem,
providing we repair a few more nerve connections...
Immediate re-deployment, right?
Ayanami...
Why is she always alone?
Evangelion Unit-01 is now in Cooling Phase 3.
No abnormalities in synchronization from the test.
Please complete all system checks in Cage 6 up to phase 3.
Desired number achieved.
Understood.
Transferring results to Valta.
Synchro Test, Program 508 complete.
Shinji-kun, good job today.
So,
how's living together with him?
So-so.
It'll take some getting used to.
Is there any leftover tension?
It's not your first time living with a man, is it?
This isn't like eight years ago.
"Love" isn't involved this time...
I wonder...
I think Shinji-kun stayed because of you.
No.
I think... he stayed because of his father.
He wants his father to see, touch, and know him.
Even just one word of praise.
He wants affection that'll stop him from feeling lonely.
He's a very distant man... like your father.
I wonder why he pays so little attention to him...
He seems to speak only to Rei.
It's a terrible balance.
Men nowadays are only interested in themselves.
It's not a very good time for women.
Well, then...
It's time we get back.
A worker bee as usual.
Misato, here's Shinji-kun's official security card
and Ayanami Rei's renewed card.
They were delivered some time ago.
Would you give them both to Shinji-kun tomorrow?
I guess so.
Ayanami Rei...
Why was my father laughing?
Why doesn't he laugh with me?
Excuse me...
Excuse me, it's Ikari!
Ayanami, I'm coming in!
Are these Ayanami's?
Um...
I wasn't trying to-
Could you move?
U-Um...
What is it?
Um, I...
I was supposed to...
T-The card! The card was renewed and...
t-that's why I...
That's why I...
I wasn't trying to...
Ritsuko-san gave it to me because she forgot...
It's the truth.
No one answered when I rang, and the door wasn't locked...
Central Dogma is currently open.
Please use Direct Gate 4 in Group 3.
Here's your new card.
Ritsuko-san left it with me.
I'm sorry for what I did.
For what?
Hey, aren't you afraid, Ayanami?
Getting into that Evangelion again...
Why?
I heard you got hurt in that test...
Are you going to be okay?
Yes.
I'll be okay.
But...
aren't you afraid it will go berserk again?
If we lose to the Angels, we'll all die...
You're Commander Ikari's son, aren't you?
You don't trust your father's work?
Of course not!
He's not much of a father...
The observed target has cleared Odawara defense line.
Unidentified object analysis complete.
Pattern blue. Angel confirmed.
As we thought, it's the sixth Angel.
Yes.
Prepare to sortie Unit-01.
Evangelion Unit-01, prepare to launch.
Moving to Cage 1 runway.
The target has cleared Lake Ashinoko.
Evangelion Unit-01 is ready to launch.
Launch!
High energy reaction detected inside the target!
What?!
Impossible!
Get out of there!
Drop the synchro rate to 0%.
Raise protective armor!
Suspend attack!
Recover Eva Unit-01 immediately!
It's no good!
The catapult is melting... It's unusable!
What about the AT Field?
It is expanded to the limit.
It is barely maintaining!
No!
No, I can't!
Let me out!
Let me out, Father!
We're breaking military protocol!
The pilot's life is our main priority!
Force eject the plug!
You can't.
If the pilot is taken out, the AT Field will completely collapse.
I know this is extremely hard to bear.
But...
Enough of this...
Force recover the fuselage!
Ignite the blasting bolts!
The target has ceased fire.
Recover Unit-01.
Sending to Cage 99!
Put the rescue squad on standby!
Plug LCL coolant at its highest level.
Pilot confirmed. Heartbeat is very weak!
Set plug suit life support to maximum.
Begin heart massage!
Yes, sir!
Pulse confirmed!
Force expel the plug!
LCL drain in progress.
Begin emergency LCL draining!
Yes, sir!
Draining LCL.
Treat him, quickly!
The target is currently invading from above.
It is burrowing into the GeoFront.
It's aiming to attack Nerve Headquarters directly?
Well then, every department report in.
Judging from the previous battle
the target seems to automatically fire on any foreign object within its space.
Then Eva won't be able to attack it directly...
How is its AT Field?
Active.
To make matters worse, it has the ability to change phase space for external protection.
Neutralizing it will be very difficult.
The MAGI estimate that N² Mines might pass through its AT Field,
but cause unnecessary damage to Nerve Headquarters.
MAGI-2 in Matsushiro has reached the same conclusion.
Presently, the Japanese Government and U.N. forces have proposed bombing Nerve Headquarters.
They sure say some outrageous stuff.
If we lose here, it's all over.
Still, it's passed through the second armored layer.
It's already begun penetrating the third.
From today, it will have to pass through 22 layers total.
It is expected to reach Headquarters tomorrow morning at 0 hours 06 minutes and 54 seconds.
That's 10 hours 14 minutes from now.
To make matters worse, Unit-00 is still not battle ready...
Unit-01 is also currently unmovable due to its previous injury.
This isn't a very good situation.
We're basically completely doomed.
Ready to wave the white flag?
Not a bad idea...
but before that, I think we should try something out.
What about the emergency battle plan from the secret agency?
Well,
you've drafted quite an insane plan, Operations Chief Katsuragi.
Don't be rude.
It takes 9 hours to implement, and it's the plan with the highest probability of success.
Operation Yashima...
It will require the electric power of the entire nation.
You even got your hands on JSSDF's secret
prototype high-output positron rifle.
It's incomplete
so it's been modified for the Eva to snipe with.
The U.N. is fine with it, though the Ministry of Home Affairs and JSSDF required some persuasion.
Well, they owe me a few favors.
Set a thief to catch a thief, I guess...
As of midnight tonight, the entire country will suffer a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation.
I repeat:
As of midnight tonight, the entire country will suffer a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation.
All right, here goes.
Yeah.
I repeat:
As of midnight tonight, the entire country will suffer a large-scale blackout.
We ask for everyone's cooperation.
The enemy has penetrated through the 7th armored plate!
What is the status of the energy system?
Electric lines will pass through transformer substations directly to Chamber 2.
Superconductivity Cable connecting to Mt. Futago is being constructed.
All voltage systems are set to direct there at 22 hours 50 minutes.
What about the sniping system?
No problems with assembly so far.
We'll be ready somehow.
What is Unit-01's status?
It is currently being fitted with the G-Mold sniping equipment.
It will be ready in another 2 hours.
Understood.
Now the only issue is the pilot.
I wonder... will he be willing to pilot it again?
What is the condition of Unit-01's pilot?
It's too soon to test the Dummy Plug.
I'll make full use of the current pilot until it's complete.
Will you brainwash him if he denies?
If he's unusable, we can simply use Rei.
Rei in Unit-01?
That's much too risky.
We must use any means to destroy the last 8 Angels.
That's when it will all begin.
I hate piloting Eva.
It's no surprise that I do well, so no one praises me for it.
If I fail, everyone will hate me.
Even worse, I could die.
Why am I here?
I came here because I thought maybe something could change... something good could happen.
Not to live my life in pain.
Will you keep living by running away from what you can't take?
Living?
Why am I alive?
I was thinking that there was no point in living.
Neither Father nor Misato-san... no one wants me.
Nobody needs me if I don't pilot the Eva.
That's why I have to pilot it.
That's why I can be here.
But, when I pilot the Eva...
The same ceiling as before.
When I pilot Eva, this is all I get.
Ayanami...
You've been here the whole time?
We are scheduled to begin Operation Yashima at 0000 hours.
Pilots Ikari and Ayanami are to report to Cage 2 at 1930 hours.
At 2000 hours, Unit-01, and Unit-00 in a support role, will transfer.
At 2005 hours, we will launch.
At 2030, we will arrive at Barricade 2 on Mt. Futago.
We will await further instructions there.
The mission begins at midnight.
Food.
I'm... not hungry.
We will leave in 90 minutes.
Then I'll... have to pilot it again.
Yes.
I've had enough.
I don't want to have those scary thoughts again.
Too frightening... And I can't run away this time...
You're afraid of Eva?
Then stay and rest.
Rest?
I will pilot Unit-01.
Ayanami!
Goodbye.
The enemy is penetrating through the 17th armored plate!
Target will reach Nerve Headquarters in 4 hours 55 minutes.
The new western Hakone line and the southern Tatsunosawa overhead line have been completed.
The Number 16 BANK is currently establishing its transformer equipment.
The 500,000 volt flow from the transformer is as calculated.
No alterations made.
The 28th unit of transformers will arrive in five minutes.
All personnel, please hasten your operations.
Initiating stage four of battle simulation.
Reconfirming the recovery and support systems.
SMES setup for all units complete.
Initiate operational confirmation from the first unit.
Operational check for all mega-high voltage superconductor transformers complete.
No problems.
That giant thing is the Positron Gun?
Even though it's still being constructed
there are no problems with the overall theory.
We will forcibly link the alignment with the G-Mold Equipment.
Well,
I hope it does its job.
The pilot's the actual problem...
That's up to you, Misato.
Shinji-kun, you're late for the rendezvous time.
You made the decision to stay here, didn't you?
Do your part in this.
I'm afraid... to pilot Eva.
You and the others don't understand.
Always giving orders from underground, where it's safe...
Only I have to experience that fear...
You're all unfair!
Come with me.
15 years ago,
the Second Impact eliminated half of humanity.
If the Angels are to accomplish the Third Impact,
humanity would surely perish.
Not one will remain.
I've heard all this before...
If an Angel ever reaches Level-EEE of Nerve Headquarters...
an Automatic Self-Destruct would commence.
It is a necessary precaution against the Angels, and the Third Impact.
Everyone here shares that resolve.
This is...
It can't be...
Eva?
No.
This is the start of all life on this planet,
and the key to the end, the Second Angel, Lilith.
Lilith...?
Yes, the trigger of the Third Impact.
To protect Lilith, Eva must fight.
Only you can pilot the Eva.
We have entrusted the future of humanity to Eva, and to you.
To do something so painful... why me?
No particular reason.
It's simply your fate.
But you're not the only one fighting with your life on the line, Shinji-kun.
We all are.
One more time.
I'll do it.
Now then, I'll explain the arrangements for this operation.
Shinji-kun.
Yes?
You will be gunning from Unit-01.
Yes.
Rei will defend you from Unit-00.
This mission will require precise, accurate operations.
For that reason, Unit-01 is more suited than the still unrepaired Unit-00.
All right, Shinji-kun?
The positron beam is influenced by the Earth's rotation and local gravity
so it will not fire in a straight line.
Don't forget to adjust for that error.
You must strike a single point of the core.
But we don't know where the core is!
It's all right.
When the target is in attack form, something materializes within it.
We assume it is the core.
Locating the sniping position, along with other various shooting factors, will be handled by us.
You just follow the manual.
When the markers line up in the center, fire.
The computer takes care of the rest.
However, this operation will require a focused point of fire.
Unit-01 will not be able to move from its firing position.
There's no retreating this time...
Yes.
What if I miss and the enemy returns fire?
Don't think about that.
Focus on destroying the target in one shot.
Else I'm screwed, huh?
I...
I am to protect Unit-01?
Yes.
Understood.
It's time.
You two go change.
Yes.
I think...
we might die this time.
No.
You won't die.
I will protect you.
I'm not much to protect.
These messages were forwarded from the PR of Headquarters to you.
Um, this is Suzuhara.
Ikari, no-
I should call you Shinji...
Shinji, do us proud.
Ah, this is Aida.
Ikari,
good luck.
Ayanami, why do you pilot Eva?
It is my bond.
Your bond?
Yes.
My bond.
With my father?
With everyone.
You're strong, Ayanami.
I don't have anything else.
It's time.
Let's go.
Goodbye.
It is currently 0000 hours.
That is all.
It's time.
Shinji-kun,
you've chosen to pilot Eva.
I'm grateful for that alone.
Thank you.
Begin Operation Yashima.
Prepare Positron Rifle charge.
Initiate first connection.
Roger.
Transferring power from water exchange unit.
All cooling systems at full power.
All transformers, maintain full operation.
0.7 seconds remaining until maximum output.
No problems found in power supply system.
Transformer frequency capacity: 65 gigawatts and rising.
All inverters still in operation.
In the process of first stage partitioning.
Opening blocks 1 through 803 circuit.
Voltage stable.
Maintaining system frequency of 50 Hz.
Initiate second connection.
Starting all accelerators. Starting converger.
Begin transfer from the new Susouno transformer.
Transferring power from Mt. Gotemba sub-station.
No issues with the breadth of the energy fluctuations.
Initiate third connection.
Roger.
Beginning connection. Transferring all energy to Mt. Futago substation.
Maintain maximum voltage for electricity transmission streams.
All connections running at maximum.
78.6% of the superconductor energy storage is charged.
Begin flywheel rotation.
Maintaining maximum energy conversion from western Japan.
No problems detected with third connection.
Understood.
Transmit to barricades 4 and 5.
We'll be acting according to plan.
After observing its reaction, take immediate action.
Defense systems 1 and 3 destroyed!
I see... nothing can pass within its space.
Next!
Barricade 2 has been hit!
VLS-08 has been vaporized!
Commence fourth attack from land.
Missile trench six, destroyed.
Laser artillery three, open fire.
Follow up with artillery seven.
Energy accumulating by positron accelerator, plus one tera.
Final rotation speed maintained at 38,000.
Increasing to the compression density discharge point.
Rapid loss in power!
Voltage conversion rate is approaching 0.019%.
Cut off the affected circuits!
Switch over!
The energy decrease is within acceptable bounds.
System circuits are operational.
Initiating system recovery.
Fourth connection complete.
No problems detected.
The final defense systems have been destroyed!
Pull back the sear!
Launcher Scope attached.
Adjust for the gravity field and revolution of the Earth by positive 0.0009.
Firing mechanism is automatically locking on.
Positron preparations complete.
The photons are accelerating. 0.2 to discharge... 0.1-
Initiate fifth and final connection!
Transferring all energy to super-high voltage discharge system.
Discharge plugs 1 through 9 are ready to accept power.
Final corrections made to the photon acceleration tube.
Pulse is safe.
No problems detected.
I don't have the same resolve as Ayanami...
And I don't have the confidence to handle Eva.
All I can do is instinctively move it for no reason.
Protecting humanity?
I don't even have a sense of its importance...
Why me?
13, 12, 11, 10...
9, 8, 7, 6...
5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
Fire!
Did we get it?!
We missed?!
It can't be!
Terrible timing...
High energy reaction detected in the target!
All hands, brace for impact!
What's the status of the Energy System?
Operational.
It's already begun to recharge.
The Positron Gun?
It's okay.
The gun barrel is now cooling.
But we don't know if it can manage another shot!
It doesn't matter. We'll do it anyway.
Shinji-kun, are you all right?!
Quickly, get Unit-01 back to firing position!
Shinji-kun?!
If Unit-01's pilot is unable to take the shot, exchange places!
We'll entrust the task of sniping to Unit-00's pilot.
Ikari!
If we're unable to use him, we have no other choice.
Please wait!
He chose to pilot Eva without running away.
Unless he chooses to fall back,
I entrust this to him!
Shinji,
do us proud!
Ikari,
good luck.
Please believe in your son!
I also believe in Unit-01's pilot!
I'll leave it to you then.
Do as you please.
Thank you, sir!
Shinji-kun.
Yes?
All of Japan's energy is with you.
All of our hopes,
the future of humanity, and every living creature
has been entrusted to you.
Good luck.
Yes!
Gun barrel in position!
Discharge system has been re-adjusted!
Unit-01's G-Mold Equipment has been discarded!
Final firing system switched to manual!
The enemy has reached the Headquarters!
It has breached the zero point!
Quickly ready the second shot!
Gun barrel fuse cooling complete!
Maintain full power output.
Evacuation of personnel complete.
No problems with any of the discharge plugs.
Firing coordinates complete!
Calculations corrected!
Minor adjustments
are in the pilot's control.
Reaching discharge pressure in 0.2.
Another high energy reading from the target!
Shit!
Shinji-kun!
Ayanami!
The shield is breaking up!
How much longer?!
20 seconds!
Hurry...
Come on... come on...
Come on!
We did it!
Ayanami!
Are you okay, Ayanami?!
Don't say "I don't have anything else."
Don't say "goodbye" before a mission... it's too sad...
What?
You're crying.
I'm sorry, but I don't know what expression to have at times like these.
I think you should smile.
Yes, I know.
That boy has awakened,
and has entered the generalization stage.
That's right.
We will move in accordance with the law written in the Dead Sea Scroll.
The time to fulfill the contract is near.
The third again, huh?
You never change, do you?
I look foward to meeting you, Ikari Shinji-kun.
It's only love
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
If I can be granted just one wish,
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
please let me sleep next to you. Any place is fine.
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumeteiru
Without regrets, my eyes are only on you.
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
You don't even know how beautiful you are
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
It's only love
netemo sametemo shounen manga
Whether you're sleeping or awake,
寝ても覚めても少年マンガ
yume mite bakka jibun ga suki jyanai no
you just dream of shounen manga, silly. Don't you like yourself?
夢見てばっか　自分が好きじゃないの
nani ga hoshii ka wakaranakute
You don't know what you want, but you can't stop wanting.
何が欲しいか分からなくて
tada hoshigatte nurui namida ga hoo wo tsutau
Lukewarm tears roll down your cheeks.
ただ欲しがって　ぬるい涙が頬を伝う
iitai koto nanka nai
I have nothing I want to tell you,
言いたいことなんか無い
tada mouichido aitai
I just want to see you again.
ただもう一度会いたい
iitai koto ienai
I can't say what I want to tell you,
言いたいこと言えない
konjou nashi kamoshirenai
maybe I'm just a coward.
根性無しかもしれない
sorede ii kedo
But that's all right too.
それでいいけど
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
If I can be granted just one wish,
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo ii yo
please let me sleep next to you. Any place is fine.
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でもいいよ
Beautiful world
mayowazu kimi dake wo mitsumeteiru
Without regrets, my eyes are only on you.
迷わず君だけを見つめている
Beautiful boy
jibun no utsukushisa mada shiranai no
You don't even know how beautiful you are
自分の美しさ　まだ知らないの
It's only love
donna koto demo yatte mite
No matter what it is, give everything a try.
どんなことでもやってみて
son wo shitatte sukoshi keikenchi agaru
Even if you get hurt, it's a valuable experience.
損をしたって　少し経験値上がる
shinbun nanka iranai
I don't need newpapers.
新聞なんかいらない
kanjin na koto ga nottenai
The important things are not printed there.
肝心なこと載ってない
saikin choushi doudai?
How are you doing recently?
最近調子どうだい？
genki ni shiteru nara
If you are fine, then
元気にしてるなら
betsu ni ii kedo
that's good I guess.
別にいいけど
boku no sekai kieru made aenu nara
If I can't meet you before my world ends,
僕の世界消えるまで会えぬなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete donna basho demo kekkou
please let me sleep next to you. Any place will do.
君の側で眠らせて　どんな場所でも結構\
Beautiful world
hakanaku sugiteyuku hibi no naka de
As these fleeting days pass by,
儚く過ぎて行く日々の中で
Beautiful boy
kibun no mura wa shikatanai ne
it's natural to feel whimsical.
気分のムラは仕方ないね
moshimo negai hitotsu dake kanau nara
If I can be granted just one wish,
もしも願い一つだけ叶うなら
kimi no soba de nemurasete
please let me sleep next to you.
君の側で眠らせて
Beautiful world
Beautiful boy
The launch of provisional Eva Unit-05.
The adoption of Eva Unit-02 and its pilot.
The disappearance of Eva Unit-04.
The forced activation testing of Eva Unit-03.
And then, Eva Unit-06 and its pilot descend from the Moon.
How long will Ikari Shinji's steadily deteriorating tale continue?
Next time, Rebuild of Evangelion 2.0: Division.
Ah, and there'll be plenty of fan service!